<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
          xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0"
          xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
            cq:isDelivered="{Boolean}false"
            cq:lastReplicated_publish="{Date}2024-07-31T09:29:32.400Z"
            cq:lastReplicatedBy_publish="workflow-process-service"
            cq:lastReplicationAction_publish="Activate"
            cq:tags="[kbank:kbank-articles/stock-market,kbank:kbank-articles/investing]"
            cq:template="/conf/wbank/settings/wcm/templates/article-page-template"
            jcr:mixinTypes="[cq:ReplicationStatus2,mix:versionable]"
            jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
            jcr:title="Common Stock: What It Is, Different Types, vs. Preferred Stock"
            jcr:uuid="60cc9e7b-81a9-435b-a5fd-54a780145bf5"
            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/page">
        <root
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                layout="responsiveGrid">
            <container
                    cq:styleIds="[1554340406437]"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                    layout="responsiveGrid">
                <image
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/image"/>
                <container
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                        layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <title
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h1"/>
                    <title_875115054
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            jcr:title="By Author Name"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h4"/>
                    <contentfragment
                            cq:styleIds="[1594172987604]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/contentfragment"
                            displayMode="singleText"
                            elementNames="main"
                            fragmentPath="/content/dam/wbank-shared/en/articles/stock-market/common-stock--what-it-is,-different-types,-vs--preferred-stock"
                            paragraphScope="all"
                            text="Common Stock: What It Is, Different Types, vs. Preferred Stock Common stock is not just a piece of paper—or, these days, a digital entry—but a ticket to ownership in a company. When you hold common stock, you get to weigh in on corporate decisions by voting for the board of directors and corporate policies. Over the long term, this type of equity can offer attractive returns. But remember, this comes with a catch: if a company has to liquidate its assets, common stockholders are at the back of the line, getting paid only after bondholders, preferred shareholders, and other creditors have gotten their share. The value of common stock issued is reported in the stockholder's equity section of a company's balance sheet. KEY TAKEAWAYS Common stock is a security that represents ownership in a corporation. In a liquidation, common stockholders receive whatever assets remain after creditors, bondholders, and preferred stockholders are paid. There are different kinds of stock traded in the market: value stocks are lower in price in relation to their fundamentals and growth stocks are in companies that tend to increase in value due to increasing earnings. Investors should diversify their portfolios by putting money into different securities based on their tolerance for risk. Common Stock Explained Common stock is primarily a form of ownership in a corporation, representing a claim on part of the company's assets and earnings. If you're a shareholder, this makes “part-owner,” but this doesn't mean you own the company's physical assets like chairs or computers; those are owned by the corporation itself, a distinct legal entity. Instead, as a shareholder, you own a residual claim to the company's profits and assets, which means you are entitled to what's left after all other obligations are met. Traded on exchanges, common stock can be bought and sold by investors or traders, and common stockholders are entitled to dividends when the company's board of directors declares them. Typically, they are paid out of a company's earnings, and the decision to distribute them is made by the board taking into account factors like company performance, future capital requirements, and broader financial goals.1 The first-ever common stock was issued in 1602 by the Dutch East India Company and traded on the Amsterdam Stock Exchange.2 Over the following four centuries years, stock markets have been created worldwide, with major exchanges like the London Stock Exchange and the Tokyo Stock Exchange listing tens of thousands of companies. Larger U.S.-based stocks are traded on a public exchange, such as the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) or Nasdaq. As of mid-2024, the Nasadaq had some 3,377 listings but the NYSE the largest in the world by market cap.34 Smaller companies that can't meet the listing requirements of these major exchanges are considered unlisted and their stocks are traded over the counter. What Is Preferred Stock? Preferred stock is a distinct class of stock that provides different rights compared with common stock. While both types confer ownership in a company, preferred stockholders have a higher claim to the company's assets and dividends than common stockholders.5 This elevated status is reflected in the name “preferred” stock. Common Stock vs. Preferred Stock Common and preferred stock both let investors own a stake in a business, but there are key differences that investors need to understand. Common Stock vs. Preferred Stock Common Stock Preferred Stock Voting Rights Holders have voting rights in the company and can participate in decisions about corporate policies and the election of the board of directors. Generally, holders do not have voting rights, although this can vary depending on the specific share terms. Dividends Not guaranteed and are paid out at the board of directors' discretion. Usually fixed it must be paid before any dividends are given to common stockholders. Liquidation Preference Holders are last in line to claim any remaining assets, following bondholders and preferred stockholders. Holders have a higher claim on assets and are paid out before common stockholders. Convertibility Cannot be converted into other forms of security. May be converted to common shares based on terms. Volatilability Generally, more since it is more alert to company performance and market conditions. Less, due to fixed dividends and a greater claim on assets. Market Participation Holders benefit directly from increases in the company's value. Typically, do not participate in the company's growth beyond the fixed dividends. Voting Rights Shareholders in a company have the right to vote on important decisions regarding the company's management. For example, shareholders vote on the members of the board of directors. Usually, common stock allows the shareholder to vote, but preferred stock often does not confer voting rights.6 Dividends Both common and preferred stockholders can receive dividends from a company. However, preferred stock dividends are specified in advance based on the share's par or face value and the dividend rate of the stock. Businesses can choose whether or not and how much to pay in dividends to common stockholders. Should a company not have enough money to pay all stockholders dividends, preferred stockholders have priority over common stockholders and get paid first.5 For holders of cumulative preferred stock, any skipped dividend payments accumulate as “dividends in arrears” and must be paid before dividends are issued to common stockholders. Trading and Price Changes Common stock and preferred stock trade on the open market. Investors can choose to purchase or sell either type of share. However, investors generally trade common stocks rather than preferred stocks. Due to their fixed dividends and lower risk profile, preferred stocks typically have less price volatility and greater growth potential than common stocks. Because of their stable dividends and lower volatility, preferred stocks are often favored by institutional investors pursuing a predictable income stream. These stocks are also normally less liquid than common stocks, meaning they are traded less frequently, making them less suitable for retail investors looking for short-term gains. Corporate Bankruptcy For common stock, when a company goes bankrupt, the common stockholders do not receive their share of the assets until after creditors, bondholders, and preferred shareholders. This makes common stock riskier than debt or preferred shares.7 The upside to common shares is they usually outperform bonds and preferred shares in the long run. Most companies issue all three types of securities. For example, Wells Fargo &amp; Company has several bonds available on the secondary market: preferred stock, such as its Series L (WFC-L), and common stock (WFC).89 Initial Public Offerings For a company to issue stock, it initiates an initial public offering (IPO). An IPO is a major way for a company seeking additional capital to expand the enterprise. To begin the IPO process, a company works with an underwriting investment bank to determine the type and price of the stock. Once the IPO is complete, the stock becomes available for purchase by the general public on the secondary market. Image by Sabrina Jiang © Investopedia 2020 Advantages and Disadvantages Both common stock and preferred stock have pros and cons for investors to consider. Pros and Cons of Common Stock Pros More frequently traded than preferred stock Higher potential returns Voting rights Cons May not receive dividends Lower priority to receive dividends or in the event of bankruptcy More price volatility Pros and Cons of Preferred Stock Pros Higher priority to receive dividends Less price volatility Fixed dividends that won't decrease Cons May lack voting rights Lower potential returns Traded less frequently How to Invest in Common Stock Stocks should be considered an important part of any investor’s portfolio. They carry greater risk than assets like CDs, preferred stocks, and bonds. However, the greater risk comes with a higher potential for rewards. Over the long term, stocks tend to outperform other investments but in the short term have more volatility.10 Investors can choose from different kinds of common stock. Growth stocks belong to companies expected to experience increasing earnings, which raises their share value. Meanwhile, value stocks are priced lower relative to their fundamentals and often pay dividends, unlike growth stocks. Stocks are also classified by market capitalization into large-, mid-, and small-cap categories. Large-cap stocks are more frequently traded and usually represent well-established, stable companies. In contrast, small-cap stocks often belong to newer, growth-oriented firms and tend to be more volatile.5 How to Invest in Preferred Stock Investors can trade for preferred stock just like common stock. However, because of how they differ from common stock, investors need a different approach when investing in them. Researching the issuing company is essential. Investing in preferred stock from a shaky company is as risky as buying its common stock. If the company fares poorly, both types of stock are likely to produce losses. One key thing to consider when choosing preferred stock is the dividend. Compare the dividends you'll receive relative to the share price to determine if the yield offers an attractive return. A better yield can result in greater returns. Moreover, take note of whether the stock is callable or convertible. Callable preferred stocks can be repurchased by the issuer at a preset date and price, causing you to miss out on future dividends. Convertible preferred stock, meanwhile, can be converted into common stock at the company's discretion, which can be an advantage if the price of the common stock rises significantly. How Do I Use Common Stock to Vote at Company Meetings? Most ordinary common shares come with one vote per share, granting shareholders the right to vote on corporate actions, often conducted at company shareholder meeting.11 If you cannot attend, you can cast your vote by proxy, where a third party will vote on your behalf.12 The most important votes are taken on issues like the company engaging in a merger or acquisition, whom to elect to the board of directors, or whether to approve stock splits or dividends. Why Is Common Stock Called an Equity? Common stock represents a residual ownership stake in a company, the right to claim any other corporate assets after all other financial obligations have been met. A company maintains a balance sheet composed of assets and liabilities. Assets include what the company owns or is owed, such as its property, equipment, cash reserves, and accounts receivable. On the other side of the ledger are liabilities, which are what the company owes. These include payables, debts, and other obligations. If a company is healthy, the total assets will be larger than the total liabilities. The residual amount left to the owners is known as shareholders' equity and is represented by a company's shares. Why Do Companies Issue Preferred Stock? Selling preferred stock, like any other shares, lets a company raise money by selling a stake in the business. A company may do this to raise capital for business expansion, debt repayment, or to invest in new projects. Preferred stocks are less dilutive of company ownership since they do not come with voting rights.6 They offer the issuing firm other benefits, not least because being less volatile makes them appeal to different investors. The fixed dividends also stabilize the company's balance sheet, making it more attractive to additional investors. Another reason is that, for some companies, the cost of issuing preferred stock is lower than issuing bonds. Unlike interest payments on bonds, dividends on preferred stock are not mandatory and generally are not tax-deductible for the corporation. However, they might still be less costly than the higher interest rates a company might have to pay to entice bond investors. Is Preferred or Common Stock a Better Investment? Each type has pros and cons. Common stock tends to offer higher potential returns, but more volatility. Preferred stock may be less volatile but have a lower potential for returns.5 This suggests that long-term investors who can handle greater volatility will prefer common stock, while those who want to avoid such fluctuations are more likely to choose preferred stock. Are There Other Different Types of Stock? Common and Preferred are the two major types. Some companies issue different classes of stock or even types of common stock. For example, Alphabet, the parent company of Google, has two classes of common stock: GOOG and GOOGL.13 The Bottom Line Common stock, as its name implies, is one of the most ordinary types of stock. It gives shareholders a stake in the underlying business, as well as voting rights to elect a board of directors and a claim to a portion of the company's assets and future revenues. However, common stockholders have a lower position than preferred stockholders, who get priority on dividend payments and in recovering their investment if the company is liquidated. SPONSORED Buy, Trade, and Hold 350+ Cryptocurrencies Join 120 million registered users exchanging the world's most popular cryptocurrencies. Purchase and trade Bitcoin, Ethereum, or BNB, Binance's native coin. Whether you're a beginner trader, crypto enthusiast, or professional, you'll benefit from access to the global crypto markets while enjoying some of the lowest fees in the business. Plus, tools and guides that make it easy to safely and securely sell, buy and convert NFTs on the Binance app."
                            variationName="master">
                        <par71
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid"/>
                    </contentfragment>
                </container>
                <container_223059690
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                        layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <title
                            cq:styleIds="[1569449156797,1568996420379,1569448853340]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            jcr:title="SHARE THIS STORY"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h5"/>
                    <sharing
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/sharing"/>
                    <separator
                            cq:styleIds="[1571075919520,1571075910473]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/separator"/>
                    <download
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/download"/>
                    <list
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/list"/>
                </container_223059690>
            </container>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
