<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
          xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0"
          xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
            cq:isDelivered="{Boolean}false"
            cq:lastReplicated_publish="{Date}2024-07-31T09:29:32.400Z"
            cq:lastReplicatedBy_publish="workflow-process-service"
            cq:lastReplicationAction_publish="Activate"
            cq:tags="[kbank:kbank-articles/market-watch]"
            cq:template="/conf/wbank/settings/wcm/templates/article-page-template"
            jcr:mixinTypes="[cq:ReplicationStatus2,mix:versionable]"
            jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
            jcr:title="Is the Stock Market Going to Crash? 153 Years of Valuation History Weighs In and Provides a Big Clue. | The Motley Fool"
            jcr:uuid="ddc91579-51d1-40b3-a69f-5c56c29c2330"
            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/page"
            pwaCachestrategy="staleWhileRevalidate"
            pwaDisplay="standalone"
            pwaOrientation="any">
        <root
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                layout="responsiveGrid">
            <container
                    cq:styleIds="[1554340406437]"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                    layout="responsiveGrid">
                <image
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/image"/>
                <container
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                        layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <title
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h1"/>
                    <title_875115054
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            jcr:title="By Rahul"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h4"/>
                    <contentfragment
                            cq:styleIds="[1594172987604]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/contentfragment"
                            displayMode="singleText"
                            elementNames="main"
                            fragmentPath="/content/dam/wbank-shared/en/articles/is-the-stock-market-going-to-crash--153-years-of-valuation-history-weighs-in-and-provides-a-big-clue----the-motley-fool"
                            paragraphScope="all"
                            text="Is the Stock Market Going to Crash? 153 Years of Valuation History Weighs In and Provides a Big Clue. | The Motley Fool We've only seen this happen six times since 1871, and the previous five instances served as a warning for Wall Street and investors. Since 2023 began, Wall Street has been firing on all cylinders. In this roughly 17.5-month stretch, we've watched the mature stock-driven Dow Jones Industrial Average (^DJI -0.24%) gain 17%, the benchmark S&amp;P 500 (^GSPC -0.01%) add 42%, and the growth-fueled Nasdaq Composite (^IXIC 0.07%) catapult higher by 69%. More importantly, all three indexes have achieved record-closing highs and firmly established themselves in bull markets. On paper, things have been going swimmingly for Wall Street. A majority of S&amp;P 500 components are topping consensus profit expectations, and the U.S. economy has remained on track. Despite a few historically accurate predictive indicators calling for a U.S. recession in 2023, the economy continues to chug along. But history also tells us that the stock market rarely moves up in a straight line for any extended period. While hype surrounding artificial intelligence (AI) is, undeniably, giving stocks a boost, it doesn't remove the possibility of equities crashing back to Earth at some point in the future. Even though there's no such thing as a foolproof metric when it comes to predicting short-term directional moves in the Dow, S&amp;P 500, and Nasdaq Composite, certain predictive tools have uncanny track records of correlating with big moves in the stock market throughout history. One such valuation indicator, which has 153 years of data in its sails, offers a big clue as to whether or not the stock market is going to crash. Are stocks heading for disaster? Over the last year, I've looked at an assortment of predictive tools that have strongly correlated with sizable directional moves in Wall Street's three major stock indexes. These include U.S. M2 money supply, the ISM Manufacturing New Orders Index, and the Conference Board Leading Economic Index (LEI), to name a few. But if there's one metric that has an extensive track record of foreshadowing big moves on Wall Street above all others, it's the valuation-driven Shiller price-to-earnings (P/E) ratio, which is also commonly referred to as the cyclically adjusted price-to-earnings ratio or CAPE ratio. With a traditional P/E ratio, a company's share price is divided into its trailing 12-month earnings per share. However, the S&amp;P 500's Shiller P/E ratio is based on average inflation-adjusted earnings over the previous 10 years. Examining a decade's worth of earnings data helps remove one-off events, such as COVID-19, which can adversely affect valuation analysis. As of the closing bell on June 13, the S&amp;P 500's Shiller P/E stood at 35.38. When back-tested to the start of 1871, this represents one of the highest-ever readings during a bull market rally. It's also more than double the average reading over the last 153 years of 17.13 -- although ease of access to public data (thanks, internet!) and a period of historically low interest rates certainly encouraged risk-taking and earnings multiple expansion over the last 30 years."
                            variationName="master">
                        <par10
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid"/>
                        <par0
                                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                sling:resourceType="dam/cfm/components/grid">
                            <image
                                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                                    sling:resourceType="kbank/components/image"
                                    alt="Stock"
                                    altValueFromDAM="false"
                                    displayPopupTitle="true"
                                    fileReference="/content/dam/wbank-shared/en/articles/stock_images_1.png"
                                    imageFromPageImage="false"
                                    isDecorative="false"
                                    linkTarget="_self"
                                    titleValueFromDAM="true"/>
                        </par0>
                    </contentfragment>
                    <experiencefragment
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/experiencefragment"/>
                </container>
                <container_223059690
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="kbank/components/container"
                        layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <title
                            cq:styleIds="[1569449156797,1568996420379,1569448853340]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            jcr:title="SHARE THIS STORY"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/title"
                            type="h5"/>
                    <sharing
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/sharing"/>
                    <separator
                            cq:styleIds="[1571075919520,1571075910473]"
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/separator"/>
                    <download
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/download"/>
                    <list
                            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                            sling:resourceType="kbank/components/list"/>
                </container_223059690>
            </container>
        </root>
        <cq:featuredimage
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="core/wcm/components/image/v3/image"
                altValueFromDAM="false"/>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
